<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Czarnecki</title>
    <description>Engineering at WB Games New York. Gamer. Foodie. Author (x3). Marathoner (x5). Snowboarder. Beekeeper.</description>
    <link>https://davidczarnecki.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://davidczarnecki.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>2018 in Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are all the video games I played in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celeste (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Far Cry 5 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minit (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;God of War (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call of Duty: Black Ops 4 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fallout 76 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darksiders III (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just Cause 4 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile (iOS):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wonderputt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kontrast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DR.MEEP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;holedown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donut County&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evergarden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alto’s Odyssey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twinfold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (console): Fallout 76&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (mobile): Donut County&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2018/12/13/2018-in-video-games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2018/12/13/2018-in-video-games.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017 in Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are all the video games I played in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resident Evil 7: Biohazard (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nioh (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prey (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Injustice 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cuphead (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Middle-earth: Shadow of War (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Evil Within 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;South Park: The Fractured But Whole (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wolfenstein 2: The New Colossus (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super Mario Odyssey (Switch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile (iOS):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remedy Rush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Breakout Ninja&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;linq&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Splitter Critters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hidden Folks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Injustice 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monument Valley 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FRAMED 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cubiques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;electronia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PUSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (console): Nioh (PS4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (mobile): Monument Valley 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2017/11/09/2017-in-video-games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2017/11/09/2017-in-video-games.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skipless</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I only listen to music when I’m running inside on a treadmill. Usually I try and pick songs that I think will keep me motivated under fast pace conditions and heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules I’ve set for the “Skipless” playlist are simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any song can go on the playlist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no limit to the number of songs on the playlist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can choose any song from the playlist to start, but subsequent songs must be shuffled at random&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a song is skipped, it comes off the playlist at the end of the run and cannot be added back to the playlist for a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it. You’ll definitely think twice before hitting the button to skip a song.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2017/02/13/skipless.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2017/02/13/skipless.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 in Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are all the video games I played in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tom Clancy’s The Division (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark Souls III (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doom (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirror’s Edge Catalyst (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inside (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adr1ft (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gears of War 4 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Titanfall 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call of Duty: Infinite Warfare (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dishonored 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch Dogs 2 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dead Rising 4 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Last Guardian (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile (all played on iOS):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploding Kittens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;twofold inc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;klocki&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Panic Drop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BLUK&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hook&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Really Bad Chess&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LVL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (console): Dark Souls III&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of the Year (mobile): klocki&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2016/12/15/2016-in-video-games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2016/12/15/2016-in-video-games.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bye Bye Birdie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My last tweet was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CzarneckiD/status/796029697272512513&quot;&gt;November 8th, 2016&lt;/a&gt;, Election Day here in the United States. Prior to that, I can’t remember going more than a few days without a tweet or, at the very least, reading Twitter. But on that night, it seemed like the Twitter-verse wasn’t a space I wanted to be a part of. Was it the seemingly endless stream of tweets and retweets from people around the country and around the world, in and out of my network, telling the figurative “me”, the United States, the world, that we had elected the wrong candidate and how fucked we would all be? Kind of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I woke up thinking, “A lot of people are going to be upset today”. But it wasn’t because of the election. It was because they didn’t have enough to eat, or a place to sleep, or adequate clothing for the coming winter, or whatever it was that had nothing to do with who was elected to the White House. After some quiet reflection at my desk, I sent off an e-mail to the local food bank to ask about volunteering. That starts today and for the forseeable future. I may change where I volunteer after a few months, but doing something is better than doing nothing to help someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, I removed my Twitter client, Tweetbot, from my iPhone, work laptop, and home computer. In the past month, I haven’t looked or cared about Twitter, for many of the reasons above. Interspersed among all the politics, I’m sure I missed a lot about your lives, but I don’t think either of us noticed. I’ll get back on Twitter in spurts, but at the very least, no longer during work. Overall I think it’s a good change. Work is no longer punctuated or interrupted all the time by the sporadic @ mention notification or the blue Tweetbot icon at the top of my screen letting me know “New Tweets Are Available”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward I’m going to work to focus my energies on things that really do have an impact on people’s day-to-day lives, like volunteering, and less on things that probably don’t, like Twittering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2016/12/14/bye-bye-birdie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2016/12/14/bye-bye-birdie.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 in Video Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are all the video games I played in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dying Light (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bloodborne (PS4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evolve (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Batman: Arkham Knight (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gears of War: Ultimate Edition (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battlefield Hardline (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mad Max (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Halo 5: Guardians (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call of Duty: Black Ops III (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fallout 4 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just Cause 3 (XB1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile (all played on iOS):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gunbrick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evolve: Hunter’s Quest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dwelp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alto’s Adventure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lastronaut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mark Ellis: Train Bridge Inspector&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TouchTone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sid The Snake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stickman Rush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boom Dots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goo Goo!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10000000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twenty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Must Build A Boat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FallMan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FireWhip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alphabear&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prune&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Domino Drop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Race The Sun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PAC-MAN 256&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sage Solitaire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wonky Ship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hocus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Round Hop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blendoku 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/12/21/2015-in-video-games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/12/21/2015-in-video-games.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 Memorial Day Races Half Marathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, May 24th, 2015, I ran the &lt;a href=&quot;http://memorialdayraces.com&quot;&gt;Memorial Day Races&lt;/a&gt; Half Marathon. The race is held in Lenox, MA at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bso.org/&quot;&gt;Tanglewood&lt;/a&gt; music venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race Venue&lt;/strong&gt;: It was easy enough finding the race entrance to Tanglewood in the AM. However, I expected there’d be some signage pointing runners to the start of the race. Waiting in line for the bathroom before the race, at least 2 people asked where the race started. I just followed the “crowd” down a paved path to the start of the race around 7:40 AM, but it’d be nice if the race organizers addressed that in future years. I say “crowd” because it’s not a large race in terms of runners. At least that oversight was unexpected given this was the 6th year of the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albanyrunningexchange.org&quot;&gt;Albany Running Exchange&lt;/a&gt; was in charge of timing the race. They’re a fantastic local organization and there were no issues at all with timing of the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race&lt;/strong&gt;: There were 206 finishers for the half marathon and 107 finishers for the marathon. Over the course of running the half marathon, there were a handful of runners I’d meet here and there, but it was largely a race without a lot of other runner or crowd contact. I do appreciate those runs where you’re able to lose yourself in the run and you can more fully appreciate the sights and sounds along the course. I did want to stop at one point towards the end of the run. There was a house that was obviously cooking breakfast as the smell of bacon wafted heavily over that part of the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I threw out the printed course map for the half marathon which had the aid stations marked. I didn’t pay much attention to the aid stations along the course as I went out with my own nutrition/hydration. The course was sectioned off on the roads around the Berkshires with cones, but the roads were still open. However, the race is run on nearly all back roads that didn’t see much traffic in the early morning, so there weren’t many cars to worry about along the course. As I remember it, the most people that I saw on the course were when the course made its way through Stockbridge, MA and passing the Red Lion Inn. So, if you’re looking for a race with a lot of crowd support, this is not that race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the elevation chart with grades for the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015-memorial-day-races-elevation-and-grades.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does get hilly in the last part of the race, but it wasn’t too terrible. At least &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; enjoyed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the race is wooded country roads after you leave the Tanglewood venue. The view highlights for me were running through the Stockbridge, MA area, in particular the Stockbridge Golf Course and the town itself. There were a few golfers out at the time I ran by, but it was otherwise very peaceful to look over the golf course covered by hint of morning fog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutrition/Hydration&lt;/strong&gt;: I had dinner the night before at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trattoria-vesuvio.com/Trattoria/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;Trattoria Il Vesuvio&lt;/a&gt;. I ordered the Zucchini Alla Parmigiana as my appetizer and the Penne Alla Vodka with a side of meatballs as my main course. I ended up tackling most of the penne and a few meatballs, but there was still a good amount of pasta that I took back to the hotel that night and ate the following day for dinner. For dessert I ordered the house made Tiramisu. Overall it was a good meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the race in the AM, I started with around 16 oz. of lemon-lime Gatorade Endurance. This has been a different approach to pre-race fueling and hydration that my running coach has started me on. I’m not entirely sold on it as it usually means I have to urinate frequently before the race. Typically I’d have knocked back a GU Energy gel 15 minutes before the start of the race. We’ll see if this approach continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out with my 2-bottle FuelBelt, using 2 10 oz. bottles. The hydration mixture was water and Nuun lemon-lime hydration tablets. I do remember slowing down at a water/Gatorade station around the 2nd mile on the course to try and see how the slow sip would work out, but I still find it too awkward to slow down and drink from a cup and run at the same time. Also, it feels too early in the race to have to slow down for water, as by then I’m settled into my pace for the race. Compared to other races, I think I was much better about pacing out my liquid intake, usually taking a sip or two every half-mile, and a few more after knocking back a GU. I went out with 3 GU Energy Gels, 2 Vanilla Bean and 1 Caramel Macchiato, and had one at miles 4 (Vanilla Bean), 8 (Caramel Macchiato), and 12 (Vanilla Bean).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the race I had a recovery shake using a recipe that my running coach gave me (greek yogurt, almond breeze, water, almond butter, small banana, and ginger powder). It’s enough calories for me to get through my post-race stretching routine and a shower before getting out to breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: My running coach had the following set out for me for this first “official” half marathon of 2015: “Start off first 3 miles conservatively then settle into half marathon pace of 8:20 min/mile. If you feel good then try to pick up the pace by 10 sec or more in the final 3 miles.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two and a half months, I’ve been running with a Garmin watch. If you had asked me last year about wearing a Garmin, I’d have shot you a dirty look, but I’m 100% sold on it now (or really any device that’ll help you know your pace during a run). It’s definitely helped me to improve my running and pacing. I’m not sure I could’ve been as consistent as I was with my splits during this half marathon if I wasn’t wearing my Garmin. There was really no timing feedback along the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up finishing with a time of 1:47:59 at an overall pace of 8:15 min/mi. As I’ve discussed with a lot of people when talking about this race: it wasn’t my fastest half marathon, it wasn’t my slowest half marathon, but I feel it was my most consistent half marathon. I ran nearly even splits the entire race, save for the few hills between miles 8 and 9 and 12 and 13. In those 2 sections, my pace was slower (around 8:40 min/mile), but compared to other half marathons with hills that I’ve run, I felt more comfortable in those sections. As with any training, it’s something I’ll be able to improve on going forward. And in the 2 miles before mile 12, I ran those at 8:02 min/mile and 8:01 min/mile, so I was happy to have some fuel for the final “fight” as my coach had set out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the next race…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/05/31/2015-memorial-day-races-half-marathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/05/31/2015-memorial-day-races-half-marathon.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Running, A Year Later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started running in earnest in March 2014. Previous to that, I had run a few 5Ks locally, and that was sporadic at best over the years. Running really wasn’t in my weekly fitness routine before last year. I do go to the gym 4x a week and have for 14+ years now to keep in shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I was going to run a half marathon and registered for the Our Towne Bethlehem Half Marathon, which was run on May 17th, 2014. I picked a half marathon training program that fit nearly exactly into the time between March and May. I finished that race in 1:42:28. Having no expectations of what is a “good” or “bad” time, I thought I ran well. My body felt fine during and after the race. During 2014, I’d also go on to run 3 other official half marathons as well: Saratoga Springs Half Marathon, Vermont Maple Leaf Half Marathon and the Melanie O’Donnell Half Marathon where I ran a half marathon PR of 1:39:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April of last year, I had also registered for the 2015 Walt Disney World Marathon. This was going to be my first marathon, however as I was training during 2014 for that marathon, I decided to register for the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon to test the marathon waters, so to speak. This was maybe a good and a bad thing. I adjusted my training routine to account for the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon and I ran that race in 3:39:34. Again, having no expectations of what is a “good” or “bad” time, I thought I ran well. I was running with the 3:35:00 pace group, but had to back off the last 4 miles as I felt my IT band in my left leg acting up and I didn’t want to injure myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a couple of weeks off after the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon to then start training for the Walt Disney World Marathon. It was aggressive, but I felt good in all my training leading up to the Walt Disney World Marathon. Until the week before … I was going to do some runs on Monday and Tuesday, but I started to feel my calf muscle in my left leg really bothering me. I’m not sure what it was that aggravated it, but I made the mental adjustment to simply enjoy the Walt Disney World Marathon and to run at a slower pace. I ended up running the Walt Disney World Marathon in 4:32:00. Certainly a slower pace and well off the time from my first marathon, but the calf muscle in my left leg that I thought would be my downfall, turned out to not hurt for the entire race. It would be my IT band in my left leg and my left heel/arch that really caused me to back off around mile 22. In retrospect, I probably should not have gone to the parks Friday and Saturday, which turned out to be around 9 and 10 miles of walking on those days. And I’m sure I needed more recovery time after the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon before starting training for the Walt Disney World Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My running goals for 2015 are simple, but aggressive: I want to run a marathon a season. I’ve already got the winter marathon behind me having run the Walt Disney World Marathon in January. For my spring marathon, I registered for the Sugarloaf Marathon in Maine, which will be run on Sunday, May 17th, 2015. That will be exactly a year since running my first half marathon and will be my third full marathon. As for the summer marathon, I was looking at the Sweltering Summer Ultra &amp;amp; Marathon, which will be run on Saturday, August 8, 2015 in Pittsfield, MA. This can also be run as an ultra marathon, so I was thinking it might be “fun” to do the 50K. And finally for my fall marathon, I’m again running the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon, which will be run on Sunday, October 11, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I started working with a marathon coach in February of this year. I knew that if I were to go it alone, without a proper training plan that encompasses nutrition, running, cross training, and strength training, I might end up doing more harm than good. And I definitely do not want that to happen. I think my instincts with respect to training and nutrition are good, but I want to do it right and professional help is going to make the other 3 marathons happen this year without injury and without the flare ups that I’ve already experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/03/09/running-a-year-later.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/03/09/running-a-year-later.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 Walt Disney World Marathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, January 11th, 2015, I ran the Walt Disney World Marathon. If you’re new to running or a seasoned veteran of the road, the running events that Disney puts on at their parks throughout the year are some of the best events you’ll run. They are extremely well organized and well attended, but most importantly are supported by a culture of encouragement and positivity. I’ve found every race I’ve run so far to be encouraging and positive, but what makes the Disney running events unique in this regard is to have so many runners (and their families and the park staff and other park guests) in the same place for an extended period of time demonstrating those traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 races held during the Walt Disney World Marathon weekend, each on subsequent days (Thursday - Sunday): a 5K, 10K, Half Marathon and Marathon. There are also a number of challenges you can elect to run, but you have to register and pay for them ahead of time. They are the Goofy Challenge (Half Marathon and Marathon) and the Dopey Challenge (5K, 10K, Half Marathon and Marathon). From what I’ve read from people who run the Dopey Challenge, they take the first 3 races very slow, with many people electing to walk. This way of tackling either the Goofy or Dopey Challenge makes them seem more approachable. In the coming years, I’m sure I’ll run the Dopey Challenge. It’s too enticing from a “Can I really do this?” perspective as well as the 6 medals (4 for each individual race, 1 for Goofy and 1 for Dopey) you receive after completing the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The medals really are a special part of the marathon weekend events. Walking around the parks, you could see people wearing their technical shirts from completing the race earlier in the AM and wearing their race’s respective medal. Everyone around the Disney properties, from the bus drivers to the cashiers to the other guests, would usually say “Congratulations” or “Great work” or offer some other form of encouragement. It always brought a smile to my face to be in an environment that was so supportive, regardless of whether you only ran the 5K or whether you ran all 4 races. Even as I was flying back home on Monday afternoon, there were so many people walking around the Orlando airport wearing their race shirts and medals and talking about the race weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different running events put on by Disney at their parks in Florida and California throughout the year. I am already looking at the Disneyland Half Marathon, which will be held over Labor Day weekend. Not only will I receive a medal for running that race, but in true Disney fashion, I’ll also be eligible to receive the Coast-to-Coast Challenge medal. This is for running a race on each coast during a calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the weekend, each Disney property is a host hotel. I stayed at the Caribbean Beach property and utilized the buses to go from the hotel to the parks, Downtown Disney, the running expo to pickup my race packet and bib, and for morning of the marathon. Buses were running continuously throughout the day and there was never more than a 15 minute wait before a bus arrived going to one of those destinations. Each of the buses to the Disney parks is clearly marked as were the special buses for the expo and to the marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I registered for the 2015 Walt Disney World Marathon on the day registration first opened in 2014. At that time, I had only run my first half marathon and provided that time, which would be used later to determine the corral I’d be in for the morning of the marathon. Each race during the weekend is broken up into corrals that start every 3-5 minutes (with fireworks). This way the runners are staggered and not running over each other. Disney gives you until mid-October to provide a better time from the time you provided during registration. I ran 3 other half marathons before the last date you could submit a better time and did well enough that I got a spot in B corral for the marathon. The 2 corrals ahead of me were the Elite and A corrals. It was gratifying to know I had done well enough to place in a starting corral, but I was more thankful that I didn’t have to stand around for an hour or more waiting before the marathon started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the races start very early in the AM. The half marathon and marathon start at 5:30 AM. For the marathon, you have to be on a bus by 4 AM to make it to your corral on time. I would suspect that the other nickname for the Dopey Challenge would be the Sleepy Challenge since you’re getting up so early 4 days in a row! The Walt Disney World Marathon weekend this year was one of the colder weekends in January for Florida. While walking around the parks on Friday and Saturday, I never saw so many people in jeans, sweaters or sweatshirts, jackets, and gloves and caps. It was almost like being back in NY weather. Almost.  All of the corrals have clothing bins so that you can wear some old clothes on race mornings, depending on the temperature, and the clothes you leave behind will be donated to charity. B corral was pretty quiet until around 5:15 AM when most of the people from the buses showed up. And even then, I never felt like I was a sardine in a can. While waiting for the marathon to start, I talked with a gentleman from the Dallas, TX area who was running his 101st marathon that morning. It was good to bond over stories of running from the past year as well as our mutual fondness for the Vanilla Bean-flavored GU gels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was supposed to be the first marathon I would run, but it turned out to be my second marathon. Last year, I felt that my training for this race was going very well, so I registered for and ran the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon. In retrospect, that was a good and bad. Good in that I went through all the motions and emotions of running a marathon. Bad in that I should have taken more time to recover after that marathon before starting to train for the Walt Disney World Marathon. The week that I was headed to Florida, on my Monday run and especially my Tuesday run, I noticed my left calf muscle acting up. I had to mentally resolve to run at a much slower pace and to simply enjoy the marathon. I wanted to finish the marathon without injury. The left calf muscle, that I thought would be my downfall during the run, didn’t act up at all. I did have a little pain in my left heel throughout and I could feel my left IT band becoming sore around mile 22. In retrospect, it wasn’t the smartest idea to have walked around the Magic Kingdom and Epcot parks on Friday and Saturday. My FitBit says I logged ~9 miles of walking on Friday and ~10 miles of walking on Saturday. You live and learn. I have a month off of running before I start training for another marathon in mid-May of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the “Pasta In the Park” party the night before the marathon. This was fun for some of the character photo opportunities, but at $65, it’s a bit pricey for a pasta dinner. You do get a special viewing area for the IllumiNations light show at Epcot at 9 PM, but I was back on the bus back to the hotel immediately after dinner to get a last stretch in before heading to bed since I had a 2:50 AM alarm set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course for the Walt Disney World Marathon takes you through all 4 parks (Magic Kingdom, Animal Kingdom, Hollywood Studios and Epcot) as well as through the Walt Disney World Speedway and the ESPN Wide World of Sports. There are plenty of water, food and medical stations throughout the course. And plenty of port-a-potties to go to the bathroom. Although, pro-tip for anyone reading this: the bathrooms in the parks are open during the race. I did briskly walk through one of the medical stations around mile 23 to slather some BioFreeze on my left IT band. One of the most fun aspects of the Disney races are the characters that you can get your picture with along the course. Some of the more popular character photo opportunities had lines with 20 or 30 people in them and I was in one of the earlier corrals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start on a road outside of Epcot and run first through the Magic Kingdom after mile 5. After exiting the Magic Kingdom and running through the Walt Disney World Speedway, it’s off on the back roads of Disney to Animal Kingdom at mile 12. Be mindful of the waste treatment facility during this stretch as it stinks. Literally. After Animal Kingdom, you make your way through the ESPN Wide World of Sports, through Hollywood Studios and finally finish back at Epcot. I wouldn’t say the first 22 miles of the Walt Disney World Marathon are largely forgettable, but after running through the Magic Kingdom, the back roads aren’t too interesting. I think one of the more fun aspects of the Disney races during the weekend is that the parks are still open. So, by the time you get to Hollywood Studios and then make your way to Epcot, there are droves of people in the parks that are also shouting words of encouragement, so it’s just a more lively part of the marathon. And that encouragement and excitement really helps during those last 4 miles or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as hydration and fueling goes, I went out with my 4-bottle pack from FuelBelt (swapped in 10 oz. bottles instead of the normal 8 oz. bottles) filled with Nuun “powered” water and I had 7 Vanilla Bean-flavored GU gels. My personal hydration and fueling approach for a marathon is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knock back one of the GUs 15 minutes before the start of the race&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few oz. of water at miles 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 25, making sure to rotate taking water from each of the bottles to keep them as balanced as possible on my hip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A GU gel at miles 8, 16, 22, and 24 with one in reserve just in case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out with my 4-bottle pack because I wasn’t going to be able to meet up with family to run with a 2-bottle pack and swap out 2 empty bottles after the halfway point. This was my approach during the Mohawk Hudson River Marathon. Personally, once I get into my running rhythm, I hate to slow up for water stations. The bottles allow me to continue to run at pace. You can’t do that with a cup of water. You only end up waterboarding yourself on the course if you try and run and drink. Thankfully I didn’t feel any lack of hydration or fueling even going at a slower pace this marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This won’t be the last running event I do at Disney. Not by any stretch. The environment is so positive and fun. And looking ahead at doing the Goofy Challenge or Dopey Challenge, I’d love to ride back home on the plane to NY wearing 6 medals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’m certainly grateful to my family for taking the time and spending the money to travel to Walt Disney World with me that weekend to run the marathon. It’s always nice to have a familiar face there to greet you at the end of a long race. But as I said, there are so many runners and staff and guests that are supportive throughout the weekend, that I can’t imagine you’d feel alone.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/01/19/2015-walt-disney-world-marathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2015/01/19/2015-walt-disney-world-marathon.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Wedding Ring</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On our anniversary, I wanted to share my thoughts with you on my wedding ring and what it means to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a man of science, I thought for sure I, or we, would end up with the Tungsten/Adamantium/Super Decoder/Wonder Twin Powers Activate type of ring. However, those rings felt cheap. They didn’t feel right on my finger. There was no weight, no significance to them. It also didn’t sit well with me that if any changes needed to be made to the ring, it would be an entirely different ring that I might get. In choosing our rings, I think of that scene from Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade where they were choosing the Holy Grail. In the end it would be a very simple white gold ring that we chose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think back to our wedding day. Holding hands in front of our family. At the start of the ceremony, we had no rings on our fingers. At the end of the ceremony, we both wore this outward symbol of our love for each other. As an introvert, I will say that I am, at times, apprehensive about the questions a wedding ring might invite. However, I will also say that the excitement of being able to talk about you or our life together, outweighs any anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the wedding ring is also beautifully simple. The two very shiny, but tiny, outer rings, joined in the middle by a larger, raised, not as shiny, inner ring. It makes me think of us. Two individuals now joined together. Initially I focused on how the inner ring would show “wear” since it was the part of the ring that came into the most contact with other things throughout the day. I wanted it to be as pristine as it was when you put it on my finger during our wedding ceremony. But I realized that the “wear” doesn’t make the ring any less beautiful, it’s just a manifestation of our life and the things that we do together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day, sometimes I’ll twist the ring around my finger and wonder if you’re doing the same thing at the same time. Cut to some side-by-side scene in a movie where the couple is separated across a house or a state or a country and they are twisting their rings at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the sound my ring makes when it brushes past your ring when we are lying in bed holding each other or when we express the call and response of, “I love you” / “I love you too” in our secret language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past two years, I haven’t taken the ring off. Not willingly. I will confess that it has slipped off in the shower a couple of times when I’m using the bath puff on my hands and it slips off accidentally. I get anxious thinking that you’ll hear the ring bounce around the shower and get upset. But I know that wouldn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wedding ring is an embodiment of our love. In some way I think of it as a representation of you. Whenever you’re not around, I can touch the ring, and in some weird way touch our love. That makes me happy. And to paraphrase our niece, it makes my heart happy. You make my heart happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy anniversary. I love you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://davidczarnecki.com/2014/12/30/my-wedding-ring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://davidczarnecki.com/2014/12/30/my-wedding-ring.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>